Contact

9007405989 (Work) anuragpatel@outlook.in

www.linkedin.com/in/ anuragpatel2301 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

R

Python

Oracle SQL Developer

Languages

English (Full Professional)
HINDI (Native or Bilingual)
Sanskrit (Limited Working)

Certifications

SQL DB5

edX Verified Certificate for Supply Chain Design

Working in teams

Introduction to Portfolio Analysis in R

Python for Data Science and Machine Learning Bootcamp

Honors-Awards

Winner at BizSense, a Big Data analytics workshop @ IIMC

PwC Data and Analytics Case Study

Build India Scholarship

Publications

Debit Card Activation and Usage Campaign using RFM Model

Anurag Patel

Assistant Manager-2, Strategy & Analytics at Citi Mumbai

Summary

I did Post Graduate Diploma in Business Analytics (PGDBA '15-17), jointly organized by IIM Calcutta, IIT-Kharagpur and ISI-Kolkata. I worked as Manager at the Data Analytics Centre of YES Bank. Worked in the areas of Marketing Analytics and Consumer Credit Analytics. I was responsible for building scorecard models, marketing campaigns and dashboards for different financial products of the bank. I also consulted different business units to provide analytical solutions to their products.

Currently I am working at the Risk Analytics unit of Citi- US Consumer Banking. I am part of the Portfolio and Strategic Analytics team. I am responsible for handling existing customers of the 11 Billion dollar portfolio of Best Buy. I am responsible for creating and implementing analytical models to achieve business growth and loss migration. I am developing, implementing and validating credit risk and marketing risk policies using machine learning models and analytical techniques for the portfolio.

Experience

Citi

1 year 8 months

Assistant Manager-2, Strategy & Analytics July 2020 - Present (2 months)

Assistant Manager-2, Credit & Portfolio Analytics January 2019 - July 2020 (1 year 7 months)

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

YES BANK

2 years 3 months

Data Scietinst- Data Analytics Centre May 2017 - January 2019 (1 year 9 months)

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

Data Science Intern

November 2016 - April 2017 (6 months)

Mumbai, Maharashtra, India

LatentView Analytics

Internship

December 2015 - December 2015 (1 month)

Kolkata Area, India

Modelling assignment for Indian Startup companies

Delivered in three stages

- 1) data cleaning and exploratory data analysis
- 2) model development and finding AUC
- 3) inference and report generation

INDIAN RAILWAYS

Summer Intern

June 2014 - July 2014 (2 months)

Summer trainee at Indian Railways' Diesel Locomotive Shed Tuglakabad, Delhi.

trained in various technology used in a diesel locomotive.

Completed a project turbo-supercharger...

UPRVUNL

Summer Intern

July 2013 - August 2013 (2 months)

Jhansi Area, India

Summer trainee at Uttar Pradesh Rajya Vidyut Utpadan Nigam Ltd.

(UPRVUNL), a U.P. government undertaking, handling thermal power stations in the Indian state of Uttar Pradesh.

trained in turbine functioning and maintenance under Turbine Maintenance Department(TMD) of UPRVUNL.

Education

Indian Institute of Management, Calcutta

Master's Degree, Business Analytics/Data Scientist · (2015 - 2017)

Indian Institute of Technology, Kharagpur

Master's Degree, Business Analytics · (2016 - 2016)

Indian Statistical Institute

Master's Degree, Business Analytics · (2015 - 2016)

Galgotias University
Bachelor's Degree, Mechanical Engineering · (2011 - 2015)

JDSVM,Kanpur